弾丸込めた小銃を　僕は片手に持っている
震えた君のいる場所へ　足を早め向かっている
チクタク　針はチクタクと
焦る心を急かしただけ
留まる気配もなく　進んでいく
チクタク　針はチクタクと
終わりと始まりの境目
全て重なった
閉口して　僕は待っていた
薄暗い部屋　一人きり
ドアを蹴破る　その音を
閉口して　僕は待っていた
薄暗い部屋　一人きり
もう怖れることはないよ
弾丸込めた小銃を持って
固く閉ざされたドアを蹴破った
吸い付いた銃口が跳ねて
昨日の僕を貫いた
おやすみ　その絶望を受け取って
明日への僕は歩き始めた
また今夜　待ち合わせよう
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:小然&千夜  翻译:maki&迩祢  校对:木落&叶隐  时间轴:Gissa  压制:久嘉
夜　夜トを助けて
Please, save Yato!
夜
Ya—
一線
Boundary!
境界
A boundary line?!
Why?!
どうして
開けてください
Please, let us in!
Daikoku-san!
大黒さん
Kofuku-san!
小福さん
お願いします
Please!
夜トが
Yato...
夜トが死んじゃう
Yato is dying!
ひよりちゃんだけこっちに来な
Only you are allowed to cross over.
小福　ひよりちゃんのやすみ　清めてやれ
Kofuku, cleanse Hiyori-chan of the blight.
Okay.
この水　庭の湧き水を直接引いてるから
This water comes directly from the spring in the garden.
Come cleanse your body.
さ　体洗って
We can use this on Yato too—
これを夜トにも
夜トちゃんのは　これじゃもう手遅れなの
It's too late to use this on Yato-chan.
What do you mean it's too late?
手遅れって
ユッキーが　罰を受けなきゃ
Yukki must be punished...
Episode 9
Name
小福　ちょっとここ頼むな
Kofuku, take over for a bit.
I'm gonna visit some shrines in the area.
俺　その辺の社回ってくるわ
Wh-What are you doing?
な　何をするんですか
How will Yukine-kun be punished?
雪音くんの罰って
禊だ
An ablution.
Huh?
え？
禊ってのはやすみを払う儀式だ
It's a purification ceremony to expel blight.
Three Sacred Tools are required. I need two others besides myself.
それには三人神器が必要だ
俺とあと二人いる
分かってるよね
You do understand what will happen if the ablution fails, right?
もし禊に失敗しちゃったら　どうなるのか
ああ
Yeah.
Anyway, we need to find the other Sacred Tools quickly.
とにかく　早く神器を連れて来ねえと
ありゃあ　明日の朝まで持たねえぞ
From the looks of it, he won't even last until tomorrow morning.
雪音
Yukine.
そこを一歩でも動いたら　ぶっ殺す
Move a single step and I will kill you.
知るか
Like I care.
Ramen
冷たい
It's cold!
夜トが本当に死んじゃうかもしれない
Yato might really die,
でも　雪音くんが受けなきゃならない罰って　何
but how must Yukine-kun be punished?
どうか　どうか　二人とも助けてください
Please... please save them both!
でも
And yet...
神様と神器は 誰が救うんだろう
For a god and their Sacred Tool...
Who actually saves them?
夜トくんが
Yato-kun's what?!
Yes.
はい
An ablution...
禊だなんて
あれって下手すると　あやかしに食われちゃうんでしょう
If done incorrectly, you'll be consumed by the Ayakashi.
え　あやかしに
By the Ayakashi?!
I had a friend who helped with a serious ablution.
私の友達にも一人いるわ
重い禊に手を貸しちゃった子
その子　どうなったんですか
What happened to her?
I don't know.
知らない
She never came back afterwards.
だって　それっきり帰って来なかったんだもの
With your permission, I would like to help.
お許しをいただけるなら　私が
ちょ　ちょっと　何を言い出すのよ
W-Wait, what are you saying?!
一度は伴の名をくださった方ですから
He once bestowed upon me the name "Tomo", after all.
Thank you, um...
助かる　えっと
真喩です
Call me Mayu.
これであともう一人
Now we just need one more...
お力添えいただきましたことを　この大黒　心に刻みます
I am most thankful for your generous assistance.
皆さんもどうか気に病まずに
Please, everyone, try not to worry,
lest it affect Michizane-sama's health.
道真さまのお体に障ります
My Lord...
公
落ちたか　夜ト
Have you fallen, Yato?!
何をやってる　バカモンが
What the hell have you been doing, you fool?!
Please!
お願いします
Would it be possible to borrow just one of your Sacred Tools?
どうか　一人お貸しいただけないでしょうか
何卒どうか
I humbly beg of you!
Please!
どうか
神器を遣わせたところで
However willing they may be, there's no guarantee that Sacred Tools can save a fallen god.
主人が落ちてからでは　助かる保証はない
But for one to afflict his master to such an extent...
大体　主人をそこまで刺す神器など
雪音を斬れ　夜ト
Yato, you must slay Yukine!
Piping
Hot
Oden
Sweet Sake
大黒
Daikoku!
Yes.
Huh?
え あと一人が見つからない
You can't find the last one?!
What are you going to do, Daikoku?!
どうすんの　大黒
In any case, I'm gonna keep asking around.
とにかく　もうちょっと当たってみるから
ああ 分かってる
Yeah, I know.
Yeah... okay...
じゃあ　また連絡する
I'll contact you later.
あとこの辺の神様といったら
All that's left are the gods in this area...
このままじゃ
At this rate...
At this rate, Yato-chan will die!
このままじゃ夜トちゃん　死んじゃうよ
Just one more...
あと一人
I've got to find one more Sacred Tool!
あと一人神器を見つけなくちゃ
野良ならきっと　夜トのために来てくれる
If I ask Nora, she'll definitely come to Yato's aid.
But...
でも　あの子はきっと
She'll also...
I will cut anything that gets in your way, nice and clean.
邪魔な者　なんだって上手に斬ってあげるよ
雪音くんを斬る
She'll kill Yukine-kun for sure.
だったら
In that case...!
Bishamon
Should you meet Veena—Bishamon again, you had best pretend she does not exist.
もしまたビーナ　毘沙門に会ったら
知らぬ存ぜぬで通せ
If you value your life, that is.
命が惜しかったらな
怖いなんて　言ってられない
This is not the time to be afraid!
カズマさん
Kazuma-san!
カズマさん　カズマさん
Kazuma-san, Kazuma-san!
丑寅の方角は異常なしか
Is that everything from the northeast?
今のところ　風穴の開く形跡はありません
At the moment, there's no sign of any new open Vents.
辰巳の方角は
What about the southeast?
はい　問題ないっす
No issues to report.
引き続き警備に当たるっす
I'll continue to be vigilant!
Kazuma-niisama, um...
カズマ兄様　あのう
先程から　カズマ兄様を呼ぶ声が
Someone's been calling for you for quite a while.
どうした　カズマ
What's the matter, Kazuma?
いえ　なんでもありません
No, it's nothing.
そんな一揖すら怠る無作法もの
Ignore it, since they don't even have the courtesy to state their intentions.
捨て置け
Okay.
はい
それでは　報告の続きを聞こう
Well then, let's hear the rest of the report.
カズマさん　お願いします　力を貸してください
Kazuma-san!
Please!
Lend me your help!
カズマさん　カズマさん
Kazuma-san!
Ka—
カっ
集まらなかったの
You couldn't get them all?!
You big dummy! Did you look as far as you could?!
ばかばかばか
ちゃんと死ぬ気で探したの
探したって
I did!
But nobody wants to help the Sacred Tool of a god they've never even heard of.
けど　聞いたこともねえ神の神器のために来る奴なんて　いねえよ
しっかりしてください
Please hold on, Yato-san!
夜トさん　夜トさん
もう　どうすんのよ
What are we going to do now...
Yato-san!
おい　一歩も動くなって言っただろ
Hey, I told you not to move a single step!
知らねえよ
Like I care!
どこへ行く
Where do you think you're going?
Kazuma...
カズマ
誰
Who is he?
夜トはどうなんだ
How is Yato doing?
お前んとこは　夜トが敵じゃねえのかよ
Isn't your group sworn enemies with Yato?!
That's true, but I'm personally indebted to him.
ああ　でも僕には借りがある
それに　あの子が呼びに来たのでね
Also...
that girl came to me for help.
ひよりん
Hiyorin!
あの子にも一言言ってやってくれ
Please give her a good talking to.
Even after I warned her, she still came to our front door.
警告しておいたのに
正面から来るとは
If Veena had found out, she would've killed her on the spot.
ビーナに知られていたら　襲われていた
まあ　どんな借りがあるか知らねえが
Well, I don't know what kind of debt you owe him, but...
これで神器が三人揃ったな
we finally have the three Sacred Tools we need.
いや　この様子では
No. From the looks of it...
this is going to be tough.
これは相当かかるぞ
Yato, can you hear me?
夜ト　聞こえているか
雪音くんの名を取って　破門しろ
You need to revoke Yukine's name, and banish him.
こんなに重篤じゃ　とても持たない
Your condition is too severe. You can't go on like this!
Yato...
夜ト
He's been like that all along.
先から　こうなんです
だから　禊をやるしかねんだよ
That's why we have no choice but to perform the ablution!
Yukine, what did you do?
雪音　何をやった
別に　何も
Nothing, really...
だったら　なぜこの場を離れようとしていた
Then why did you try to leave?
What does it matter?!
どうでもいいだろ
後ろめたい思いがあるからじゃないのか
Is it because you're feeling guilty?
うざいからだよ
I'm just sick and tired of all of you!
どいつも　こいつも
何もしてねえっつってんだろ
I told you I didn't do anything!
そうか
Is that so?
Then take off your shirt.
だったら　ちょっと上脱いでみろ
Huh?
なんでだよ
Why should I?
いいから　黙って脱げ
Just shut up and strip!
Yuki
What the hell is this?!
なんだ　これ
てめぇ　そんなに主人を刺したのか
Damn you! Did you sting your master that much?!
Are you ready?
Get it off me!
キメェ
覚悟はできてるな
何しゃべってる
取ってくれ　早く
Get it off!
早く取ってくれよ
Hurry!
夜ト神に捧げし　御霊拭いて
We cleanse the Spirit consecrated in the name of Yatogami,
and preserve the name with which it was graced.
賜りし御名を守らん
What?
何
汚れ払いて　俗心は無に
Cleanse all impurities and expel all defilement,
that there may be a clean, upright, and righteous soul.
赤き　直き　正しき魂
Prune and pare all manner of flesh, that he may be pure.
禊身削ぎて　清くあれ
獄
Imprison!
Noragami
N
o
r
a
g
m
i
What's going on?!
何
An ablution is a ceremony that can rend the flesh.
禊とは　身を削ぐこと
This is a lynching, performed by Sacred Tools with their Boundary lines.
これは神器が境界線を使って行う　リンチよ
Lynching...
リンチって
As former humans, only Sacred Tools can punish the sins of another.
神器の罪は　元人間である神器たちにしか裁けない
Let me out! Let me out, damn you!
出せ　出せ　こら
And once the ablution begins,
そして禊は初めたら最後
it must be seen to the end.
途中でやめるわけにはいかない
It can't stop until the Sacred Tool confesses and repents all its sins.
神器が自分の罪の全てを洗いざらい吐き出し
懺悔しない限り
Yukine! What evil deeds have you committed?
雪音　何悪さやった
Confess!
全部吐け
Shut up!
うるせえ　殺すぞ髭
I'm gonna kill you, you beardy!
If he doesn't...
さもないと
This is bad!
まずい　あやかしに転じる
He's turning into an Ayakashi!
Don't look!
見ちゃダメ
Stop it!
もうやめて
This is cruel!
こんなのひどい
This is too cruel!
ひどすぎる
What did I do?!
俺が何したってんだ
I didn't do anything bad!
俺は何も悪くねえ
It's not my fault!
悪いのは俺じゃねえよ
All this... for some loose change...
たかが小銭くらいで
こんな
That's right!
そうだよ　盗ったよ　奪ったよ　壊したよ
I took things, I stole money, I smashed things!
And what's wrong with that?!
だからなんだよ
You guys get it too, don't you?
あんたらだって分かるだろ
'Cause we're all dead!
死んでんだからさ
I mean...
だって
They have everything!
だってあいつら
全部持ってる
I had a fight with my parents.
親と喧嘩した
I asked my big brother to help.
兄ちゃんに手伝ってもらったんだ
We're friends, right?
友達だろ
ほら見て
ファイト
The future... memories... families... friends...
未来も　思い出も　家族も　友達も
They have them all...
あいつらには全部あるのに
Why don't I have them...
なんで俺にはねえんだよ
Why can't I have anything?!
なんで俺には何もねえんだよ
That's right.
そうだ
By the time I realized it, I was already alone.
気づいたら一人だった
I had nothing.
俺には何もない
Nothing.
何も
You really do have beautiful eyes.
やっぱりキレイな目
Like Hawthorn fruit blown by the wind.
風に揺れる山査子の実みたい
But...
でも　その実は鳥も食べないね
not even birds would eat them.
They're neither sweet nor bitter.
甘くもなく苦くもない
Public Disaster Relief
Donation Box
Thank you for your support
They're not poisonous, and yet provide nothing for the body.
毒でもないけどちにくにもならない
Just useless, empty fruit.
役に立たない空っぽの果実
With no one to pick them, they grow stale.
誰にもついばんでもらえずに色褪せ
Without being connected to anything, they wither and die.
何とも繋がらず　枯れてなくなるの
What a pitiful boy...
可哀想な子
What's wrong with taking everything?
全部奪って何が悪い
What's wrong with destroying it all?
全部壊して何が悪い
Everyone... should be just like me...
皆　俺みたいに
and die!
死ねばいいんだ
It's no good!
ダメ　もう　これ以上は
At this rate...
Daikoku!
大黒　黒器になってこいつを倒せ
Turn yourself into Kokki and destroy him!
Don't panic, dumbass!
パニックってんじゃねえ　ボケカス
If I do that, the whole barrier will fall apart!
俺が抜けたら決壊するだろうが
Besides, if I turn into Kokki, I'll just open more Vents!
だいたい　黒器じゃ時化さして意味ねえんだよ
Use your brains for once, Mr. Elite!
もっといい手ねえのか　エリート
The mark!
印が
If it gets enveloped, it's all over!
あれが飲み込まれたら　もう
Don't give up!
諦めんじゃねえ
His name...
名前
I have to call out his name...
あいつの名前
呼んでやんねえんと
Before it disappears...
名前が消える
Capypa-Land
After all, I fell for him at first sight.
なんだって　俺が見初めたやつだからなぁ
Before he crosses to the other side...!
あっちに行ってしまう
I need... to call... his name...
名前
名前を
Yukine-kun!
雪音くん
Hiyorin!
ひよりん
This is dangerous, stand back!
危ない　下がってろ
Yukine-kun!
雪音くん　そっちにいっちゃダメ
Don't cross over to the other side!
Don't turn into an Ayakashi!
あやかしになんかならないで
You still have Yato, don't you?!
雪音くんには夜トがいるじゃない
You must have heard his voice!
雪音くんだって聞こえていたはずよ
He might be a shitty brat,
こいつは碌でもねえクソガキだが
but I found and named him!
俺が見つけて　俺が名付けた
I will reforge you, Sekki!
雪器は俺が鍛える
He spoke to you like a father!
あの言葉
まるでお父さんだった
Even when...
夜トは　夜トは
Even when you continued to betray him, and hurt him,
雪音くんに裏切られて　刺され続けても
Yato endured it!
ずっと耐えていたのよ
If you're going to betray someone like him...
そんな人をまだ裏切るなら
then we can't be friends anymore!
もう友達じゃないからね
Fr—
と
Friends...
友達
Yukine!
雪音
It's true,
確かに
you can no longer live on equal terms with those in the Living World...
お前はもう此岸の人間と 対等に関わることはできない
But Yukine...
だが　雪音
I gave you a human name!
お前には人の名を授けた
So...
だから
So live as a human being!
だから人として生きろ
Live, Yukine!
生きるんだ雪音
I...
ご
I... I'm sorry...
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry!
ごめんね
ごめんなさい
I hurt Yato!
俺が夜トを刺しました
I stole money!
金も盗ったし
I even...
ひよりをさ　触ろうとした
I even tried to feel up Hiyori!
I stole a skateboard!
スキーボーも盗んだし
And I broke some glass windows!
ガラスも割りました
I lied a lot too!
嘘も沢山つきました
I won't do it anymore!
もうしません
I'm really, really sorry!
本当に本当に　ごめんなさい
I'm sorry!
ごめんなさい
Souvenirs
Eatery
Shima-ya
Rest
Stop
Okay, all clear!
はい　二人ともオーケー
I thought I was gonna die...
死ぬかと思った
But you're already dead.
もう死んでるよ
This is why I hate handing out punishment...
これだから仕置きは嫌なんだ
I'm sorry for all the problems this idiot caused.
このバカのためにすまねえな
You have my thanks.
礼を言う
You can say that again.
全くだよ
I never thought I would have to trouble Hiyori like this too.
ひよりにも
こんなに面倒を掛けるとは思わなかった
Yukine, get over here.
雪音　こっちこい
Sorry!
すまん
You should apologize too!
お前も謝れ
I'm sorry, Hiyori.
ごめん　ひより
If...
もしここに連れてきてもらわなかったら
If she hadn't brought me here, I would've died right then and there.
あのまま死んでいたかもしれない
If she had picked Nora as one of the Sacred Tools,
もし　連れてきた神器が野良だったら
the pain would have been unbearable, and I could have used her to kill Yukine.
苦痛に耐えかねて
野良で雪音を斬っていたかもしれない
And if she hadn't stopped Yukine like she did...
もし　雪音を呼び止めてくれなかったら
If Hiyori wasn't around...
もし　ひよりがいなかったら
She...
こいつは
She saved us all!
俺達を救ってくれた
I'm so glad... you're both okay!
よかった
二人共無事だった
I'm sorry, Hiyori!
ごめん　ごめんね
ひより
Thank you.
ありがとう
君の名前 何があっても
必ず呼ぶから
君はぎざぎざハートの持ち主
触れるものは何でも傷つけ
世界のすべてを睨み付けて
その目は言うんだ
「僕はここにいる」
誰かが笑ってた
だから引いたんだ その境界線
それなら
私はその手を引く
さぁ
連れてくから
言えないなら
この手を強く握って
離さないで
君はもう一人じゃないんだって
知ってほしいんだよ
I see the stew has begun to froth...
あぶくたった　煮え立った
Is it ready to eat yet? Let's taste and see.
煮えたかどうだか食べてみよう
Munch, munch, munch.
むしゃむしゃむしゃ
That boy should have been consumed by the Ayakashi.
あの子あやかしにむしゃむしゃ食われちゃうと思ったのに
I was right to wake you up after all...
やっぱりあなたに起きてもらって正解だったわね
Rabo.
ラボう
I see the stew has begun to froth...
あぶくたった　煮え立った
Is it ready to eat yet? Let's taste and see.
煮えたかどうだか食べてみよう
It's ready now.
もう煮えた
Yato...
夜ト
is that really the Yato who was formerly the god of calamity?
あれが本当にかつてのまがつがみ 夜トなのか
You can always see it for yourself.
自分で確かめてみればいいのよ
Next time on Noragami, "Regarded with Hate."
次回ノラガミ
忌むべきもの
By the way, my name is Mayu.
というわけで初めまして　真喩です
Come to think of it, this is the first time we've met. I'm Daikoku.
そういや　初対面か
俺は大黒だ
I'm Kazuma. If you'll please excuse me, I must go.
カズマだ
すまないが　僕はこれで失礼する
Me too.
S-Sure.
私も
Those two are really similar to each other...
またな
Next Episode
Regarded with Hate
あの二人　意外と似てるね